Within the TCP model, layers have devices,
protocols, and applications used at each layer.
For example, on the Application Layer, we
have all the software pieces of data, such
as the application protocols, HTTP, DNS, and
others, and data formats such as text and
image formats.
Encryption takes place on this layer and the
use of session protocols such as RPC and PPTP.
On the transport layer, TCP is the main protocol.
IP is the main protocol on the Internet layer,
and we start to see hardware come into the
model, as routers are used on this layer.
On the Network Access layer, switches and
the media used to transmit data, such as Ethernet
cables, are featured.